It all starts here.
In order for my wish to be granted...
I'll try my best!
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
... The girl who wishes.
Kobato!
Yes, Ioryogi!
You've finally arrived.
You know that this is the human world, where humans live, right?
Yes, I understand!
Whether your wish is fulfilled or not depends upon your efforts here.
You know that too, right?
Yes, of course!
If you understand...
Then why do you have to hang out here all day!
Come on, talking like this is fun! It's so secretive!
Hanato Kobato!
What is your wish!?
There's somewhere I want to go!
And just what do you need to do to get there?
I have to fill a bottle with scarred hearts!
And before that?
I need to get a bottle!
And what do you need to do to get a bottle?
I need to pass a test by my actions here or something!
That's right!
Today, we're gonna check whether you have the common sense needed to make it in the human world.
The test has already begun, under my supervision and judgment!
Do you understand!?
I understand!
The criterion for the test is how well you can exhibit the basic knowledge relevant here.
Go for it, Kobato!
Show me proper behavior in this springtime park!
Okay!
Fine!
What shall I do, Ioryogi?
What are you doing, hibernating!?
Come on!
Can't you even properly enjoy yourself in the park?
Sorry.
Come on, you--
Oh man.
Why don't I even have time to take the trash out?
I won't catch the bus!
Sorry!
No problem!
Oh no, I'm gonna be late!
Ioryogi!
She dropped it.
Very well, time for your next test.
Show me what you're going to do with that trash.
Okay!
Hmmm, where should I throw out trash?
That's it!
Here!
Here?
I can--
You can?
There's crows.
They're after the trash. Hurry up or they'll be after you.
They're after it?
The crows are after the trash?
Crows! Here you go!
What the hell are you doing!?
You scared me.
What are you doing trying to get the crows' attention!?
They looked hungry, so I thought I'd tame them by feeding them the trash.
You're not even a "Kobato"! "Dobato" is good enough!
You're so mean.
Hey, you.
You alone?
Let's go get a cup of tea.
Tea?
There's a great teahouse right around here.
Are you just trying to pick her up in broad daylight?
C'mon, it's my treat.
You're treating? Thanks!
All right, let's go.
Okay!
Isn't that nice, Ioryogi?
Dobato!
Just what did you come here for!?
But he's treating!
Are you okay!?
I'm gonna...
He's hurt!
What the hell did you just do!?
Hey, don't give me that crap!
Damn, you're annoying.
What, you had your boyfriend with you!?
Excuse me!
Thank you!
Quit making such a big deal about it.
I'm not just making a big deal!
Well, if you grin like that, people are gonna think so.
Man, I'm glad it's sunny today.
It'll be busy with all the people out to see the cherry blossoms.
Right, Fujimoto?
That's right.
This one's done.
Okay.
What a cute kitty!
Here.
I'll take that plate for you.
Okay.
He's so cool!
Why don't you ask his name?
Go for it!
You could do better, Fujimoto.
Maybe you'd be more popular with the girls if you smiled a bit.
I'm not really interested.
You're such a bastard.
Sorry, I forgot to turn it off.
Fujimoto speaking.
What's wrong, Miss Sayaka?
He showed up at the nursery again?
Hold on, I'll be right there.
Sorry, boss, something just came up!
What's going on, Ioryogi? There's so many people here!
Probably here for the cherry blossom festival or something.
Man, that smells great.
Let's go take a look.
That's right! Let's go take a look!
They're in full bloom!
It's so pretty!
Hey lady! Toss that back to us!
Okay!
Sure thing!
Thanks, lady!
Here goes!
There!
What are you doing!?
I'm so sorry!
No use crying over spilt milk.
I'm really so sorry!
And I'm already shorthanded...
Let me help out!
Let me help out as an apology!
Another beer on that order!
Gotcha!
You're really picking this up quick. Thanks.
Really!?
I'm so glad I could help!
Well, it's not unusual for Kobato.
Hey, where's my nabe?
Here!
One here.
Are you even listening to me?
Here you go!
Sorry, but can I watch?
Please?
Come on.
Me...
Make a nabe?
This can be a test too.
Kobato, show me your skill at making nabe!
Hey, you can't put those in until it boils!
Don't put the meat in yet!
Why are you putting milk in!?
What? Come on, it's healthy!
Why chocolate!?
People cheer up when they eat sweets!
No more natto!
It's a horror show.
But let's not waste it.
Huh?
Tasty!
Boss, you should try some too!
It's tasty.
Really!
It's tasty!
This is great!
I think we'll be adding this to the menu, young lady.
Thank you!
She's pretty good for her age.
I thought they'd just try a little, but they're still going.
Who do you think you are, Kobato?
You get zero points for your knowledge of nabe back there, Kobato.
But it did turn out pretty good.
I'll give you 40 points.
Come on!
There, there.
What's wrong?
He just won't stop crying.
Sorry!
It's not your fault. Don't worry about it.
But--!
He always gets like this at night.
I bring him to this park a lot so as not to disturb the neighbors.
He won't sleep until he's all worn out.
I see.
His mother always used to be with him.
She'd always sing to him when he cried, and calm him down.
Where is she now?
Right now, she's working hard for his sake.
So I'm doing my best to take care of him.
But my singing voice doesn't calm him down at all.
Let me sing.
Let me sing for his sake.
Even though I don't think I can do it as well as his mom.
Please do.
Okay!
I'll sing my best!
The flowers which blossom in spring
Are plucked in the summer sun
Within my heart
It's fine, I'm already back at work.
Don't worry, Miss Sayaka.
Wow, this song...
Even on days I close my windows
Fluttering within my heart
The light breaks through the clouds
A faraway voice leads me on
Like it's smiling, like it's singing
The echoing sound of the wind
Joy and sadness
Well, at least she's good at singing.
I embrace them both and keep going
She's just like Kohaku.
My hand and yours
Join together strongly
Wow, she's amazing.
Um... I...
That was wonderful.
He stopped crying.
That's great.
It's all thanks to you, young lady.
Let me hear it again!
Sing more!
Let's go over there, there's a stage!
Let's hurry!
They brought us so many gifts.
Well, no problem taking them in exchange for singing.
Then...
Umm, how'd I do on the test?
The test, huh.
Hanato Kobato!
Yes!
You made a total mess of the first half.
How well you did with the nabe during the second half was pure luck, too.
Well, I guess the song was okay.
Then--!
You failed!
Didn't you just say the song was okay!?
You did too bad during the first half!
Meanie! You're so mean!
I tried my hardest!
Well, you almost made it.
Too bad.
Come on!
Young lady.
The granny from before!
Good evening.
Good evening, young lady who's good at singing.
I'm glad we've met again.
Thanks again for before.
I wanted to say something to thank you.
This is the first time he's enjoyed anyone's song but his mother's that much.
He cheered up and went right to sleep.
Sorry for not even thanking you after you sang for my grandson.
No, I don't mind.
Your singing really is wonderful.
I'd like to hear it again sometime.
Okay!
Anyway, goodnight.
Yeah, goodnight!
Hey.
Hanato Kobato!
Yes!
You passed.
This... is a bottle, isn't it.
Yeah.
It's the real thing, isn't it.
Yeah. What the granny said there was worth a hundred points.
You passed the test.
It's really the real thing!
If you don't like it, give it back!
Sorry, it's fine!
If I can heal scarred hearts and fill this bottle with their shards...
Your wish will be granted.
But so far you've just got the bottle.
Yes!
Hanato Kobato! What is your wish!?
There's somewhere that I want to go.
And what do you need to do to get there?
I must fill this bottle with scarred hearts.
This is just a warmup, okay?
You've still got a long way to go!
Yes!
I'll try my best!
Man, you're overdoing it.
What are you so happy about, Dobato!?
You're so mean!
My name is Kobato!
Hanato Kobato!
Dobato's good enough! If you don't like it, I can call you Dabada instead!
Okay, fine, Dobato!
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you say it thankfully, if you do it thankfully
Together, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... Sparkling candy.
Next episode